Guide to the Ricardo Sánchez Papers, 1941-1995
Department of Special Collections
- SERIES I: Manuscripts by Sánchez, c. 1962-1994.
  - Subseries #1. Sánchez manuscripts
    - Articles, El Paso Herald Post (July-Dec., no year) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Articles, El Paso Herald Post (no date) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Articles, Richmond Afro-American (1969) (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Articles, Richmond Chronicle (1969) (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (March 1985) (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (April 1985) (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (May 1985) (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (June 1985) (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (July 1985) (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (August 1985) (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (Sept. 1985) (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (Oct. 1985) (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (Nov. 1985) (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (Dec. 1985) (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (Jan. 1986) (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (Feb. 1986) (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (March 1986) (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (April 1986) (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (May 1986) (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (June 1986) (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (July 1986) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (August 1986) (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (Sept. 1986) (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (Oct. 1986) (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (Nov. 1986) (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (Dec. 1986) (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (Jan. 1987) (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (Feb. 1987) (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (March 1987) (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (April 1987) (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (May 1987) (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (June 1987) (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (July 1987) (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (August 1987) (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (Sept. 1987) (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (Oct. 1987) (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (Nov. 1987) (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (Dec. 1987) (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (Jan. 1988) (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (Feb. 1988) (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (March 1988) (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (April 1988) (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (May 1988) (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (June 1988) (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (July 1988) (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Articles, San Antonio Express-News (miscellaneous) (Box 3, Folder 26)
      Sánchez's files re: San Antonio Express-News, including articles, correspondence and notes
    - ["As we bask..."] (1980) (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - "as you marshall images/resources" (1992) (Box 3, Folder 28.1)
    - "at Rico's 5 Aug 93" (1993) (Box 3, Folder 28.2)
    - "Aurora Landín" (1993) (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - "AUTOBIOGRAPHY OF A BATO..." (1970) (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - "Aztlán..." (1970) (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - ["Bárbara..."] (1980) (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - "Barrio Sound" (1995) (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - ["Bearded, monk like carnal-..."] (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - "Bellas" (1977) (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - ["Bertrand and the Mehkgoverse"] (1989) (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - "beyond farewells" (1979) (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - ["Beyond the madness..."] (n.d.) (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - "Bibliomanias" (1986) (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - "The Bisons::Los Bisontes" (1990) (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - ["Bopping sounds..."] (1985) (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - "¿Brindar o no brindar?" (1987) (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - "bronce florido" (1978) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - "BROWN BEAR HONEY MADNESS: Alaska Cruising Poems" (1979) (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - ["Bujandejo..."] (1991) (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - "Cachos curtidos" (1982) (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - "Cafecito con Leche" (1992) (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - "canto a Eugenio - para Yevgeny Aleksandrovich Yevtushenko" (1993) (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - "Canto a Felipe Ortego" (1992) (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - "Canto a Jacinto-Temilotzín" (1976) (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - "CANTO A LIBERTAD-YVONNE..." (1970) (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - "canto a Lorena y Rolando" (1992) (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - "Canto a Milwaukee" (1977) (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - "Canto Blue[s]" 1st Rough (1988?) (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - "CANTO: de La Oreja a El Chuco" (1988) (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - "CANTO for NAVAJO WOMEN" (1974) (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - "Canto Navideño" (1978) (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - "Canto que te quiero, Canto: un brindis poético a Felipe Ortego y Gasca y también a MECha/U.T.E.P." (1985) (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - "Canto to a loved Abuela" (1992) (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - "CANTOS A RICK SCARCE" (1993) (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - "cantos europeos refritos" (1979) (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - "Cantos of Gold & Joys: an Anniversary Poem to Felicita y Alberto Acevedo" (1992) (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - "cantos vitales, poesía y amores" [pages 1-20, original and copy] (1983) (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - "cantos vitales, poesía y amores" [pages 1-117] (1983) (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - "cantos vitales, poesía y amores" [pages 118-317] (1983) (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - "Cantos y llantos y gritos refritos somos mas que las sombras que vivimos..." (1970s) (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - "caras carísimas caras" (1991) (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - ["caras encarbonadas..."] (1988) (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - "cariños navideños" (1987) (Box 4, Folder 29)
    - "Carnival: a review of Dona Flor and Her Two Husbands "(1979?) (Box 4, Folder 30)
    - "CARTA/Magda/CARTA y otras misivas" (1990) (Box 4, Folder 31)
    - "cartulinas" (1986) (Box 4, Folder 32)
    - "Casa Joaquín Murrieta" (1985) (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - "Centro América" (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - "el chavo" (1985) (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - "CHICANO" (1991) (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - "Child" (1990) (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - ["chills speak..."] (1982) (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - "chivas, batos y claws" (1987) (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - "the clarion sounded" (1991) (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - "Cleta y Neta" (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - "cobble strewn canals" (1978) (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - "COLORES/PUEBLOS" (1988) (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - "Con Más Caras..." (1983) (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - ["Con un poema..."] (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - ["Contradictory images.."] (n.d.) (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - "Coronado" (1972) (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - "Corrido de Río Dorrado" (1981) (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - ["crazy, weird..."] (1969) (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - "CROSSING BORDERS" (1992) (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - "la Cruzada Dorky" (1987) (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - "Cuando" (1978) (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - "Cultura is San Antonio" (1981) (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - ["Cumbias ricochet..."] (1990) (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - "CUNA: poetics/prosa cúmulo y cumbre toward a new definition of experiential Chicano Life" (1974) (Box 5, Folder 23)
      Ph.D. dissertation, Union Graduate School-original
    - "CUNA: poetics/prosa cúmulo y cumbre toward a new definition of experiential Chicano Life" (1974) (Box 5, Folder 24)
      Ph.D. dissertation, Union Graduate School -copy
    - "CUNA: poetics/prosa cúmulo y cumbre toward a new definition of experiential Chicano Life" (1974) (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - "dance & sing, o memories - poetic sketches for Lena C. Sánchez" (1986) (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - ["Dearest Mother..."] (1983) (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - ["defoliate the lawn..."] (1988) (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - "Demented Theme"[?] (1962-1972) (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - "dirge chicaneaux - a canto for César" (1993) (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - "Diversity and Growth: a review of MESTIZO: Anthology of Chicano Literature" (1978?) (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - "D[octo]r. Sánchez's All-You-Can-Eat Poetry Buffet" (1994) (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - "dos días después" (1992) (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - "los draggy chukes" (n.d.) (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - ["dreams dance..."] (1987) (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - for Robin, "THE DRUM..." 3 thoughts on being Chicano: "To La Causa...", "When..?", "Having Lost..." (1970) (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - "Duality IS a Joyous Song" (1984) (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - "duelos, sonrisas, promesas y" (1986) (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - "EAGLE VISIONED/FEATHERED ADOBES: manito sojourns & pachuco ramblings" (1981) (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - "Earthiness, Honesty, and Rusticity: The Poetry of José Montalvo: an intro" (1983) (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - ["en el espíritu de Quetzalcoátl..."] (1978) (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - "En el Mundo De las Artes" (n.d.) (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - ["en este día de las madres..." ](n.d.) (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - ["En este día tan bello..."] (1984) (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - "en mi méxico fuera de México" (n.d.) (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - "en su caló..." (1987) (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - "Encuentros" (n.d.) (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - "encuentros" (1986) (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - "End of a Dream?" (1972) (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - "en-ojitos: canto a Piñero" (1988) (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - "Entelechy: On Human Freedom in Prison" (1980) (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - "Entelechy/ Entelequia II" (1989) (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - "Entelequia III" (1978) - Screenplay (Box 6, Folder 21)
      See also Entelequia files in SUBJECT series.
    - "Entre lo bien recorrido de" (1979) (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - "eres, eras, serás::ontology" (1993) (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - "erótica, 1970" (1970) (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - "ese, brodita, can ya spare" (1993) (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - "Ese, pues, that's the way it is" (1965) (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - "espontáneo - spontaneous..." (1969) (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - "esquemas y montajes" (1988) (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - "evening melody for Shareese" (1988) (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - "Evolution: Madness/Unsanity" (1973) (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Excerpts from Sojourns (1976) (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - "Exilio: a thoughtpoem for Héctor Marroquín" (1978) (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - "Falcón" (1972) (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - "Festival Fronterizo/postizo: UCSD, Imperial Valley Campus" (1977) (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - "Festival of Children" (1980) (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - "Les Fils of the Barrio:ze onda, mon ami" (1988) (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - "FLORiMOQUIANDO: thoughtfeelings y cantogritos..." (1976) (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - "For Fred, un canto" (1992) (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - ["for within poverty..."] (1980) (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - "fraggies sans veggies" (1992) (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - "fragments" (1984) (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - "fuerza femenina" (1981) (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - "LAS FUNDACIONES DE LOS PUEBLOS" (1984) (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - ["gentle strength..." ](1993) (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - ["glaciered reflections dance..."] (n.d.) (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - "hacen muchos años, más..." (1981) (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - ["Haré del deseo..."] (1975) (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - "HAVING LOST..." (1970) (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - ["He sauntered..."] (1989) (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - ["He visto..."] (1982) (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - "HECHIZOS" (1970) (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - "HECHIZOS" (1970) (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - "Hope, Horizons, and Humanity" (1984) (Box 7, Folder 1)
      immigration
    - "horizontes y ensueños" (1988) (Box 7, Folder 2)
      Peoples of Color Task Force on Social and Criminal Justice
    - "HUES & FACES IN ALL PLACES" (1985) (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - "Human Culture" (1984) (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - ["I am mesmerized by people who think while projecting beauty..."] (1973) (Box 7, Folder 5)
      La Causa
    - "I Celebrate" (1992) (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - ["idea gloriosa..."] (1980) (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - "IMAGES...a poem in fragments" (1988) (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - "IMMIGRANT PLUCK" (n.d.) (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - "IMPRESSIONS: SAN FRANCISCO" (1972) (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - "IN and OUT: a journey from the barrio to the movement..." (1972) (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - "IN & OUT: ramblings and thoughts..." (1969) (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - ["in cavernous moments"] (1989) (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - "In Exile: The Only Chicano Outpost in the Olde Commonwealth Of This Here Virginny..." (1969-1970) (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - "in friendship to Jesús Alvarado" (1989) (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - "In the colours of our humanity" (1984) (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - "In Windy Wor(l)ds..." (1984) (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - "INDICT AMERIKA" (1970) (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - "inside the lens of Sinthia's Nikon" (1990) (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Interview with Sánchez, conducted by Rafaél Castillo (1984) (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - "INTROSPECTIVA: para Teresa" (1977) (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - ["it is a birthing day..."] (1992) (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - "It was not an impressive moon..."] (1989) (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - ["JAGGED, hurting land..."] (n.d.) (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - "los jívaros tambíen hacen su jive" (1988) (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - "Jornada in 3/4 Tempo" (1991) (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - "JORNADAS DE UN CHICANO: reflexiones de un pinto y bato loco con papeles y voz" (1986) (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - "JORNADAS: poetic sketches written especially for "A" Magazine" (1978) (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - letter poem to Joe Renteria (1971) (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - Journeys through the Pass: BLOODIED TRACKS & DESERTLAND POEMS (1990) (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - "JUAREZ FANTASY..." (1969) (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - "July 14, 1968: a Visit " (1968?) (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - "just as" (1991) (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - "L.A. People: Accion Chicano" (1973) (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - "LAMENTO Y CANTO: The Blues of El Flaco In the Still of his Inmenso Corazón...A Poetical Perspective" (1993) (Box 8, Folder 6)
      Jesus "El Flaco" Maldonado
    - "let me have..." (1982) (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - "Letter to My Ex-Texas Sanity" (1977) (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - "Letter: to self (six fragments)" (1985) (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - "Life's Arbitrariness" (1984) (Box 8, Folder 10)
      ENCAJES: column
    - ["llegué encabronado..." ](1982) (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - ["Lo digo yo, Netzahualcoyotl..."] (n.d.) (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - "LOQUEANTE" (1977) (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - "love strewn sands" (1990) (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - "loveliness rides" (1981) (Box 8, Folder 15.1)
    - "lovely woman ..." (1979) (Box 8, Folder 15.2)
    - "LULAC: A Half Century of Human Rights and Cultural Celebration" (n.d.) (Box 8, Folder 16)
      Proposal for media program, proposed by María Luisa Gonzalez and Abraham J. Vázquez, written by Sánchez
    - "the making::a preface," "the dis-re-making::a postface" (1989) (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - "THE MAL-CREATION OF HISTORY, or IF THIS IS AZTLAN, I'D RATHER BE IN THE HYSTERIA OF ASLUM" (1985?) (Box 8, Folder 18)
      Review of THE LEGEND OF LA LLORONA and THE ADVENTURES OF JUAN CHICASPATAS, by Rudolfo A. Anaya
    - "Mania" (1964) (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - ["Marginalized, struggling..."] (1979) (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - "mecha..." (1971) (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - "meshis refritos" (1988) (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - "México" (1991) (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - "Míctla: Long Road Home" (n.d.) (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - "Migrant lament..." (n.d.) (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - "MILHAUC BLUES y other things..." 1977 (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - Mind Spew (proofs) Malcontent Press (1992); "Introduction" and "A Bato Loco Market Trip" by Sánchez (Box 8, Folder 27)
    - Inroduction to Mind Spew (1992) (Box 8, Folder 28)
    - ["miro caras encarbonadas..."] (1983) (Box 8, Folder 29)
    - "monde d'chicano" (1988) (Box 8, Folder 30)
    - "los monos y los poetas" (1987) (Box 8, Folder 31)
    - "MOSAICO CHICANO/ensayo, cuentos, poemas" (1987) (Box 8, Folder 32)
    - "mujer del barrio..." (1971) (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - "el mundo se vuelve en-canto" (1993) (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - ["nacimos, pueblo..."] (1988) (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - ["need exists..." ](1993) (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - ["noche salada..."] (1980) (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - "non ode to a gava novelist &" (1988) (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - The Northwest Cantos, Part I (1992) (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - "notas a Federico (con disculpas y festejos) - un homenage a Federico García Lorca" (1987) (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - "notas de Riverside" (1989) (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - Notes (n.d.) (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Notes (1985) (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - Notes (Aug. 1986) (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Notes (Dec. 1987) (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Notes (Oct. 1992) (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Notes - John Igo (n.d.) (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Notes - "Money changers in the temple" (n.d.) (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - Notes - Nephtali de León (n.d.) (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - "notes on a child in a city bus" (n.d.) (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - "NOTES ON THE PAST/HOPES FOR THE FUTURE" (1980) (Box 8, Folder 51)
      Criminal Justice Ministry; Catholic Charities; Kansas State Penitentiary
    - "NOTES, sketches, & Ondas" (1984) (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - "o MEChA" (1991) (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - "o youth, o life" (1992) (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - Obituary for Pedro-Cuauhtémoc Sánchez (n.d.) (Box 8, Folder 55)
      infant son of Ricardo and Teresa Sánchez
    - "Oda a los cantos" (1989) (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - "oh, woman, ay, mujer" (1993) (Box 8, Folder 57)
    - "old man" (1972) (Box 8, Folder 58)
    - "on life" (1992) (Box 8, Folder 59)
    - "On Writing" (n.d.) (Box 8, Folder 60)
      Centro Cultural Aztlan; Viaztlan
    - "Once" (1980) (Box 8, Folder 61)
    - "Once for another moment: to the beauty of children in room 8, Nelson Elementary School, San Anto[nio]" (1987) (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - "El One Day Late Cantina" (1975) (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - "órale, Rolando" (1992) (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - "Palousean Poets" (1992) (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - "pantallas" (1986) (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - "pasaron - a cantogrito, a prosepoemsong intertwining songs and moods, an experiential praxis..." (1975) (Box 9, Folder 6)
      Chicaspatas Cultural Adjustment Center LTD; El Pachuco Te(de) Jaslum
    - ["Pasión me fataliza..."] (1969) (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Pelagatos and other writings (1980s) (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - "Pembroke" (1971) (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - "Pensamientos y" (1980) (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - "pieces of Guernica" (1989) (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - "PIENSASENTIMIENTO CHICANO: POETICA DE LA RAZA" (1979) (Box 9, Folder 12)
      G.I. Mixco (co-editor); Giantonio Pozzi
    - "Un PIENSASENTIMIENTO PARA María Teresa Silva Sánchez" (1976) (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - "PIENSO Y CANTO: 1970 CHICANISMO" (1970) (Box 9, Folder 14)
      Also includes program from "HISPANO-AMERICA: The Enigma of Culture..."
    - "pintagráfica" (1986) (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - PINTO: obras escogidas, Pages 1-109 (1984) (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - PINTO: obras escogidas, Pages 1-98 (1984) (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - PINTO: obras escogidas, Pages 100-159 (1984) (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - PINTO: obras escogidas, Pages 175-205 (1984) (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - PINTO: obras escogidas, Assorted pages (1984) (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - PINTO: obras escogidas, Complete manuscript (1984) (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - PINTO: obras escogidas, excerpts for anthology in Spain (1988) (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - "pisto" (1974) (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - "Un poema de amistad y compañerismo Para Mike Conroy y Mary Young bajo el patrocinio de Michael Greenstein" (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - "Poema en Canto" (1994) (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - "poemario en Tejas...Sketches & Gestos" (1986) (Box 10, Folder 6)
      Title page and table of contents only
    - "poemas, flores, y llamas -- to Roberto Sifuentes in compañerismo..." (1984) (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Poems (1963-1975, n.d.) (Box 10, Folder 8)
      On notepads
    - "poems for a St. Valentine's Day Massacre of arts & letters" (1988) (Box 10, Folder 9)
      Cover sheet only
    - Poems inspired by La Luz (1975) (Box 10, Folder 10)
      Also includes June 1975 issue of La Luz
    - "Poems submitted" (1990s) (Box 10, Folder 11)
      Includes "poets three," "quartered century," "symbiont spaces," "symbiont spaces: urbe," "notes on an artist's death," "urgencia," "urgencia II: Stanfordian," "Arizona Bus," "there is no time," "Canto to life/sense"
    - "Poesía Chicana: Enigma Societal" (1971) (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - ["la poesía es..."] (1988) (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - "Poesie Contra American Me Modalities - A Response to Edward James Almost" (1993) (Box 10, Folder 14)
      Edward James Olmos; Washington State University, Semana de la Raza
    - ["poetic greeting..."] (1990) (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - "P(oética) - 79: One World Poetry" (1979) (Box 10, Folder 16)
      P79
    - "Poet's View" (n.d.) (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - "PRESO POLITICO..." (1970) (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - "Primer Dama de Nuestro México Querido" (1981) (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - "PRISON REMEMBRANCES..." (1983) (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - "processing" (n.d.) (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - "Proud People" (1971) (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - "¿que se ama - la mujer o las mujeres?" (1975) (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - "Questions" (1982) (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - "QUESTIONS::MOOT/SALIENT OR REFRACTIONS..." (1983) (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - ["Quick witted..."] (1986) (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - "La Raza: Chicano - Poems, thoughts, feelings" (1970) (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - "Raza Survival/Realization" (1993) (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - "razgos" (1985) (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - "Recuerdos: sketches from the past..." (1983) (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - ["reflections dance about..."] (1981) (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - "Regeneración..." (1971) (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - "remember" (1986) (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - "Rio Dorado," Working Draft No. 1 (April 20, 1987), Part I (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - "Rio Dorado," Working Draft No. 1 (April 20, 1987), Part 2 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - "Rio Dorado," Working Draft No. 2 (May 23, 1987) (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - "Rio Dorado," Working Draft No. 3 (July 23, 1987) (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - "Rio Dorado," Working Draft No. 4 (July 30, 1987) (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - "Rio Dorado," Working Draft No. 5 (May 17, 1987) Episode I (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - "Rio Dorado," Working Draft No. 5 (Sept. 24, 1987) Intercut for last draft (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - "Rio Dorado," Working Draft No. 6 (Sept. 16, 1987) Final Cut, Episode I (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - "Rio Dorado," Working Draft No. 7 (Sept. 29, 1987) (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - "Rio Dorado," Working Draft No. 8 (Oct. 15, 1987) (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - "Rio Dorado," Extra Scenes (1987) (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - "Rio Dorado," Cover pages (1987) (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - "Rio Dorado," Rough (March 19, 1987) (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - "Rio Dorado," Rough No. 2 (March 20, 1987) (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - "Rio Dorado," Master Scene Outline, Rough No. 3 (November 20, 1987) (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - "Rio Dorado," Master Scene Outline, Rough No. 5 (November 23, 1987) (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - "Rio Dorado," Master Scene Outline, Rough No. 6 (November 24, 1987) (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - "Rio Dorado," Master Scene Outline, Rough No. 7 (November 25, 1987) (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - "Rio Dorado," Master Scene Outline, Rough No. 8 (November 30, 1987) (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - "Rio Dorado," Master Scene Outline, Rough No. 9 (November 31 [sic], 1987) (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - "Rio Dorado," Master Scene Outline, Rough No. 10 (April 1, 1987) (Box 12, Folder 11)